Let's get started with the web pack entry.
现在开始学习 webpack 入口 (entry)
Web pack entry is the first major concept of web pack,
入口是 webpack 的第一个主要概念
and what it's going to do is give us
它要做的就是提供
a starting place for web pack to begin to build its dependency tree.
一个用于 webpack 构建依赖关系树的起点
So what we need to do is set up that entry point for web pack in our web pack config.
因此 我们要在 webpack 配置中设置该入口点
In your application that you started with and cloned from GitHub.
在你从 GitHub 克隆并开始工作的应用中
Right now, we have one web pack config file and in that web pack config file,
现在已经有一个 webpack 配置文件 在这个配置文件中
we are requiring a few things but really it's empty.
我们编写了一些 require 但实际上还是空的
That's great, but we need to actually start building on to this so that we can run it.
目前做的不错 但是我们需要真的将其构建出来才能运行
Now, in our package.json,
现在 在 package.json 中
you should see that you have web pack and web pack CLI both installed.
你应该看到已经安装了 webpack 和 webpack-cli
But what we need to do now,
现在要做的就是
is actually add an NPM script that allows us to run web pack.
实际添加一个 npm 脚本 使我们可以运行 webpack
So I have added this here,
我已经在这里添加了
the build web pack and this is an NPM script.
"build": "webpack" 这是一个 npm 脚本
You can write as many custom NPM scripts as you want.
自定义 npm 脚本你想写多少都可以
This one, is just going to run the web pack command.
这个脚本只是用来运行 webpack 命令的
Now, we're going to add more to the actual command. Part of this later.
我们稍后会添加更多实际使用的命令
But just for a very simple demonstration,
不过为了目前这个简单的演示
we're going to just run the word web pack.
现在只运行这句 webpack
I'm going to save that file,
保存这个文件
and then we're also going to come back to our web pack config file,
然后返回到 webpack 配置文件
and we're going to add an entry.
添加一个入口
Now, web pack in Version 4,
在版本 4 的 webpack 中
has a default entry but this entry we're making
有一个默认的入口 但我们需要自定义该入口
custom because we have a client folder that web pack,
因为我们用了一个 client 文件夹
the default doesn't plan for.
与 webpack 默认值不相符
So we are declaring an index.js file inside of client,
所以我们声明了 client 文件夹中的 index.js 文件
that is going to be the starting point where web pack will begin to build our tree from.
是 webpack 构建树的起点
So now that we have this entry point declared,
现在声明了这个入口点
we can go and run web pack in the terminal.
就可以在终端运行 webpack 了
So I'm going to use my new NPM script and we'll run this build command.
因此 我将使用新的 npm 脚本 运行这个 build 命令
When we do that,
运行之后
we find that we're getting an error, but in this case,
发现遇到了错误 但是在这种情况下
the error is a good error,
该错误是有意义的
and we're getting this error because it can't resolve source in users video.
出现此错误是因为 webpack 无法解析 users/video… 路径中的 ./src
Really, what this is telling us in a not-so-great way,
这实际上是用一种不太好的方式告诉我们
is that the client index.js file doesn't exist and we need to create it.
client/index.js 文件不存在 我们需要创建
So if we look at our source folder here,
查看一下这里的 src 文件夹
we're saying that inside of source and inside of client,
我指的是 src 文件夹中的 client 文件夹
there's going to be a new file called index.js.
里面要有一个名为 index.js 的文件
Once we have that,
有了这个文件之后
we'll be able to run web pack and successfully see it built.
就能够运行 webpack 并且能看到其构建成功
So now, when we run the NPN build command,
现在 运行 npm 的 build 命令
we should see a different output.
应该能看到输出和之前不同
We see that there's no longer an error.
看不到错误了
Instead, we see this part,
取而代之的是这个部分
this green part which is a really good sign.
这个绿色的部分 绿色是非常好的信号
We see that a main.js file,
我们看到创建了一个 main.js 文件
was created and that it is currently 0 bytes,
目前这个文件大小为 0 字节
which is okay, we're still getting there.
这不是问题 现在还没到那一步
So this means that web pack was successful.
这意味着 webpack 运行成功
If we go back to our index.js file and we just want something to show up,
如果我们回到 index.js 文件 想显示出一些内容
we just want to see some JavaScript.
想看到一些 JavaScript
So I am going to do an alert and we
那么 我来添加一个 alert 操作
should see that reflected in our new built five.
应该就能看到这行代码体现在新构建的文件中
So when that runs,
重新运行
we can now see that the main.js file was created and that it is 17 bytes.
现在可以看到 main.js 文件已经创建 大小是 17 字节
Now, the really cool thing is that if we go back and look at our project structure,
现在 真正有趣的是 如果回头看一下项目结构
we see a new folder.
可以看到一个新文件夹
This folder was not there when I started,
这个 dist 文件夹开始时并不存在
I didn't create it,
我没有创建过
it's been generated by web pack.
它是由 webpack 生成的
So when we open it and we take a look,
打开它看一下
we see that we have a main.js which is exactly what web pack
其中有一个 main.js 文件 这正是 webpack
said that it built and if we take a look through it,
创建的 如果打开文件浏览一下
there's a ton of code here that we did not write.
里面有很多不是我们编写的代码
Everything in here, has been generated by a web pack and there's no real magic to it.
这里的一切都是由 webpack 生成的 不存在什么魔法
But if we do a find for an alert,
但是如果我们查找一下 alert
you can see that my alert is right there.
可以看到 alert 也在这里
This is the piece of code that I put into index.js
这是我在 index.js 中编写的代码
and it's being created into our web pack bundle for us.
它被创建输出到 webpack 文件包中